このアングルだと　一部の生徒しか映らないな
I can only see a few of the students from this angle.
Gotta love the face of a junior-high student in pain.
いいなあ　中学生が苦しむ顔
Once I get that ten billion yen,
１００億円手に入れたら
中学生たくさん買って　毎日ウイルスのまそうかな
I might just buy a bunch of 'em and force-feed 'em that virus every day.
Fourteen—no, fifteen of them.
１４…　いや１５匹か
呼吸も若い　ほとんどが１０代半ば
Judging by their breathing, they're young, mostly in their mid-teens.
Who'da thunk it?
驚いたな
動ける全員で乗り込んできたのか
Everyone who's still up and about made it here.
言っとくが　このホールは完全防音だ
Just so you know,
this hall is completely soundproof.
お前ら全員撃ち殺すまで　誰も助けに来ねえ
I'll fill you all with lead before anyone comes to save you.
You know that none of you have the guts to take a life.
お前ら　人殺しの準備なんてしてねえだろ
おとなしく降参してボスに頭下げ…
Now come on out like good little children and bow before the boss—
Missed! And I was aiming for the gun!
外した　銃を狙ったのに
Live ammo? And from the sounds of it...
実弾
しかも　今の発砲音は…
手下のＭ６０を奪ったのか
Did they take our goons' Model 60s?!
暗殺の訓練を受けた中学生か
Junior-high kids trained for assassination...
Excellent.
いいねえ
意外と　うめえ仕事じゃねえか
Looks like this might actually be a job I can sink my teeth into!
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
起立
礼
ロックオン
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
起立
礼
ロックオン
Oh yeah!
oh yeah
The target is our teacher!
sensei target on
せんせー
ターゲットオン
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
ポテンシャル高い
We've got a lot of potential
potential takai
ポテンシャル高い
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
ポテンシャル高い
It's just that we're not trying
hodo mendokusai
ポテンシャル高い
ほどめんどくさい
总监.Maki
台本.小伍
We had that dropouts' mentality
dropout mentality
ほどめんどくさい
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
No matter the unusual situation we were in
hinichijou wo ryougashi
翻译.兰樱
非日常を凌駕し
校对.Maki
翻译.兰樱
非日常を凌駕し
校对.Maki
We pretended to doze off
bokura wa utatanegao shite
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
僕らはうたたね顔して
While holding on to a hidden knife
knife kakushimotta
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
僕らはうたたね顔して
时间轴.歪歪
BDRip.VCB-Studio
ナイフ隠し持った
起立
Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on
礼
ロックオン
Thinking someone would deal with you eventually
hottokeba kitto dareka yatte kureru to
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
どこか　他人事だった
We didn't really feel invested in the job
doko ka taningoto datta
どこか　他人事だった
だけど
But now
dakedo
だけど
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
Teacher, teach us, we're still growing up
mister teacher oshiete mikansei na bokura
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
Will we be able to shoot through an invincible target like you?
anata to iu furaku no target uchinukeru deshou ka
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
As long as we challenge you, it's fifty-fifty
Stand, bow, lock on!
idomu kagiri kanousei wa half and half
kiritsu rei lock on
挑む限り　可能性はハーフ＆ハーフ
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
Teacher, watch us, as we try to find a direction in life
mister teacher mite ite mayoi ooki bokura
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
We're studying our ass off for you more than anybody else
dare yori mo anata no tame ni moubenkyouchuu sa
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
殺意だけが　あなたへのメッセージ
Only the bloodlust is our message to you
satsui dake ga anata e no message
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
殺意だけが　あなたへのメッセージ
We'll make our dreams come true on our own for real
jiriki gachi de hongan iku yo
自力　ガチで
本願　行くよ
A revolution!
revolution
レボリューション
Oh yeah!
oh yeah
The target is our teacher!
sensei target on
せんせー
ターゲットオン
Episode
XX
Time
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 及微博 @诸神字幕组
ま…まぶしい
S-So bright!
逆光でステージが見づらい
Can't see the stage with that backlight!
Feelin' fine again today, with my tasty, tasty gun!
今日も元気だ　銃がうめえ
H-He fired through that tiny gap?
こ…こんな狭い隙間を通して
一度発砲した敵の位置は忘れねえ
I never forget the position of any enemy once they've fired.
俺は軍人上がりだ
I used to be in the military, you see.
幾多の経験の中で　敵の位置を把握するすべや
My time there gave me a knack for pinpointing my enemies' locations,
銃の調子を味で確認する感覚を身に付けた
and having to identify guns with my tongue gave me a real taste for weaponry.
さあて　お前らが奪った銃はあと１丁あるはずだ
Now, then... There should be one more stolen gun out there.
速水さんはそのまま待機
Hayami-san! Remain standing by!
今　撃たなかったのは賢明です
You were wise not to fire just now, Chiba-kun!
千葉君
君はまだ敵に位置を知られていない
The enemy still doesn't know where you are!
先生が敵を見ながら　指示をするので
I'll keep an eye on him and tell you when,
ここぞと思うときまで待つんです
so hang tight until it's go time!
な…　どこからしゃべって
Where's that coming from?
てめえ　何　かぶりつきで見てやがんだ
Hey! Quit starin' at me from the front row!
熟練の銃手に中学生が挑むんです
An expert gunman versus junior-high students?
このくらいの視覚ハンデはいいでしょう
I think it's fair for them to have a slight handicap.
Okay, Kimura-kun, run five seats left!
では　木村君　５列左へダッシュ
寺坂君と吉田君は　それぞれ左右に３列
Terasaka-kun and Yoshida-kun, move three seats to either side!
We've formed a blind spot!
死角ができた　この隙に茅野さんは２列前進
Kayano-san, use this chance to move two rows forward!
業君と不破さん　同時に右８
Karma-kun and Fuwa-san, move eight seats right!
磯貝君　左に５
Isogai-kun! Five seats left!
シャ…シャッフル　ややこしいまねしやがって
H-He's shuffling them around?
Bastard's making it complicated!
And yet,
だが　指示する程に名前と位置を俺に知らせることになる
he's telling me their names and positions with every command.
あっという間に覚えちまうぜ
I'll have 'em memorized in no time.
Student number 12!
出席番号１２番　右に１で準備しつつ
Move right and continue preparations!
４番と６番は椅子の間からターゲットを撮影
Numbers 4 and 6, film the target from between the seats!
律さんを通して　舞台上の様子を千葉君に伝達
Use Ritsu-san to tell Chiba-kun what's happening onstage!
Ponytail, move to the front-left!
ポニーテールは左前列へ前進
バイク好きも左前に２列進めます
Motorcycle Fan, you too! Two seats to the front-left!
最近竹林君一押しのメイド喫茶に興味本位で行ったら
The person who visited Takebayashi-kun's favorite maid café out of curiosity and was alarmed to find he liked it,
ちょっとはまりそうで怖かった人
かく乱のため　大きな音をたてる
make a big racket to confuse the enemy!
うるせえ　何で行ったの知ってんだ　てめえ
Shaddup! How the hell did you know that?!
全然分からなくなってきやがった
Now I have no idea where anyone is!
Okay, Chiba-kun, it's time.
さて　いよいよ狙撃です　千葉君
After I give this next command, fire at will.
次の先生の指示の後　君のタイミングで撃ちなさい
くそ　どこだ
Argh! Where are you, dammit?!
速水さんは状況に合わせて　彼のフォロー
Hayami-san, support him as the situation requires.
敵の行動を封じることが目的です
You're looking to block off the enemy's movements.
が　その前に表情を表に出すことのない２人に　先生からアドバイスです
But before that, a word of advice for the two who don't let their feelings show:
君たちは今日　先生への狙撃を失敗してしまったことで
When you failed to shoot me down earlier today,
自分たちの腕に迷いを生じさせている
you began to doubt your own skill.
言い訳や弱音を吐かない君たちは
You don't whine or make excuses,
あいつらだったら　大丈夫だろうという
and your classmates forced their confidence onto you,
勝手な信頼を押し付けられることもあったでしょう
thinking, "Surely they can handle it."
苦悩していても　誰にも気付いてもらえない
No one would notice your anguish.
こんな成績で　何涼しい顔してんのよ
You seem pretty relaxed for someone with such bad grades!
あんたを信じて任せた私がバカだったわ
I should never have trusted you to study on your own!
He won't even make any excuses.
言い訳もしないあの子が何考えてるか　私　さっぱり分かんないのよ
I have no idea what he's thinking!
でも　大丈夫
But it's all right.
君たちはプレッシャーを１人で抱える必要はない
You don't have to bear all that pressure alone.
君たち２人が外したときは　人も銃もシャッフルして
If you two miss, we'll switch to plan B: shuffling people and guns around
クラス全員誰が撃つかも分からない戦術に切り替えます
so no one can tell who's pulling the trigger.
We can use that strategy because everyone here has gone through training and tasted failure.
ここにいる皆が訓練と失敗を経験しているからできる戦術です
君たちの横には　同じ経験を持つ仲間がいる
You have allies at your side who have shared your experience.
安心して引き金を引きなさい
So with that peace of mind, go ahead and fire.
Heh. Thanks for that.
ありがとよ
That little pep talk of yours gave me enough time to figure this out.
ご高説の間に　ある程度目星が付いたぜ
出席番号１２番ってやつが１人だけ動いていない
Student number 12 is the only one who hasn't moved.
そのくせ　呼吸は何やらたくらんでやたら荒い
And yet they're breathing heavily, like they're planning something.
あの近辺を出た瞬間　仕留める狙いを付けておいてやる
The second someone pops up in that area, I'll shoot to kill.
では　いきますよ
All right, here we go!
味は最高　今の俺は人銃一体
It tastes divine!
Right now I'm one with my gun...
外す気がしねえ
and I don't plan on missing!
出席番号１２番　立って狙撃
Student number 12! Stand and fire!
ビンゴ
Bingo!
な…　人形
A dummy?!
That's where you need to aim!
狙うなら　あの一点です
オーケー
Okay.
外したな
You missed. Now I know where the second one—
これで２人目も　場所が…
Th-They aimed for the brackets...
つ…つり照明の金具を狙っただと
on the stage lights?
くっ…　くそが
Damn it all!
Phew. Finally hit the mark.
やっと当たった
よし
All right, tape him up!
す巻きだ
Building a dummy in complete silence takes a lot out of you!
音立てずに作ってたから疲れたぜ
肝を冷やしたぞ　よくこんな危険な闘いをやらせたな
That was a real white-knuckle moment.
I'm amazed you let them handle such a dangerous fight.
どんな人間にも　殻を破って大きく成長できるチャンスが何度かあります
Every human being has a number of opportunities to break out of their shell and grow.
しかし　１人ではそのチャンスを生かしきれない
But they can't make the most of those opportunities on their own.
よーし
さすがだな
集中力を引き出すような強敵や
They need tough foes who call on their powers of concentration
経験を分かつような仲間に恵まれないと
and allies with whom to share their experiences.
だから　私は用意できる教師でありたい
And so, I want to be a teacher who can provide these things.
To give my students high walls and good friends without losing sight of their moments of growth.
生徒の成長の瞬間を見逃さず
高い壁を　良い仲間を揃えてあげたいのです
何て教育だ
What an education.
命懸けの撃ち合いをした後なのに
They've just had a shoot-out with their lives on the line,
表情はむしろ闘う前より中学生だ
and yet their expressions look more like junior-high students' now.
Seems like I'm back in action.
だいぶ体が動くようになった
Though I'd say I'm at about half strength.
まだ力半分ってところだがな
That's still twice as strong as us.
力半分ですでに俺らの倍強え
He should have just gone in alone.
あの人　１人で入った方が良かったんじゃ…
この上が最上階なんだよね
So that leads to the top floor.
Yeah.
We're out of time.
もう時間がない
Students!
皆さん
I've come to realize something about our mastermind waiting above.
この上にいるであろう黒幕について分かってきたことがあります
He's using assassins all wrong.
彼は殺し屋の使い方を間違えている
What?
何
Lookout and guards... Those aren't jobs for assassins.
見張りや防衛など　それは殺し屋の仕事ではない
If their potential had been used to the fullest, they'd have been fearsome indeed.
彼らの能力はフルに発揮すれば　恐るべきものです
Yeah, the gunman's shot wasn't even a single centimeter off the mark.
確かに　あいつ　狙った的は１ｃｍたりとも外さなかった
And, Karma-kun: if that fellow had sneaked up on you from behind on any other day,
業君も日常で後ろから忍び寄られたら
あの握力に瞬殺されていたでしょう
he would have killed you instantly through sheer grip strength.
I suppose so.
そりゃね
So it's true.
やはり　黒幕は殺し屋ではないということか
Our mastermind isn't an assassin after all.
Time to assign roles to each of you.
個々に役割を指示していく
First off...
まずは磯貝君　寺坂君　吉田君　君たちには…
Isogai-kun, Terasaka-kun, Yoshida-kun:
渚
Nagisa?
I'd like you three to...
You're burning up, Terasaka-kun. Are you...
すごい熱だよ　寺坂君　まさか…
infec—
ウイル…
Keep it down!
黙ってろ
I always got stamina to spare.
俺は体力だけはあんだから
It'll go away by itself in no time!
こんなもんは放っときゃ治んだよ
そんな　無茶だよ
That's crazy talk!
That damn Karasuma only got gassed 'cause I had to go and run ahead when I did.
烏間の先公がまひガス浴びちまったのは
俺が下手に前に出たからだ
And that's not the first time my actions almost got everyone killed.
それ以前に　俺のせいで　クラスのやつら殺しかけたこともある
I ain't about to drop out now and drag everyone down even more!
こんな所で脱落して　これ以上足引っ張れるわけねえだろ
Terasaka-kun...
Commence operation!
寺坂君
C'mon!
いくぞ
Ooh, Namba!
おお　ナンバ
They say ninjas used this walking style.
忍者も使うといわれた歩方
No wonder there've been so many more silent assassinations in our classroom lately.
どうりで　最近の教室では　物音をたてる暗殺が減っていた
Even as their time runs out, they refuse to panic or lose hope.
一刻を争う緊急時なのに　決して焦らず悲観せず
I'm so proud of these students of mine.
全員が私の自慢の生徒です
All the more reason we mustn't give in to the enemy before us.
だからこそ　決して目の前の敵に屈してはいけませんよ
I'm betting that's the viral remedy.
あれがおそらくウイルスの治療薬だ
And those wires...
配線の仕掛けは　プラスチック爆弾
They lead to a plastic explosive.
We're right on time.
打ち合わせどおりだ
Ideally, we'll be able to subdue him.
取り押さえることができれば　それがベスト
If he sees us, I'll shoot his arm.
もし気付かれたら　俺の責任で犯人の腕を撃つ
He won't be able to push that detonator...
起爆スイッチは押させない
and that's when we all rush in and grab them!
それと同時に　みんなで一斉に襲い掛かって拘束する
Now!
今
Itchy.
かゆい
The very memory makes me itch.
思い出すと　かゆくなる
But maybe that's why my senses have grown so much keener—
でも　そのせいかな
いつも傷口が空気に触れるから
because my wounds are always exposed to the air.
感覚が鋭敏になってるんだ
Didn't I tell you? I've come prepared to kill a Mach-20 monster.
言ったろ
もともとマッハ２０の怪物を殺す準備で来てるんだ
I brought spare detonator remotes in case one was snatched away at high speed.
リモコンだって　超スピードで奪われないよう　予備も作る
I have more than enough to press any one of them if I should fall.
うっかり俺が倒れ込んでも　押すくらいのな
We'd heard that voice before...
聞き覚えのある声だった
but this time, it was far more sinister.
しかも　前よりずっと邪気をはらんで
Of the people I couldn't reach, there were three assassins and one other.
連絡がつかなくなった人物は　３人の殺し屋の他にもう１人いる
An insider who vanished with Ministry of Defense secret-service funds and the assassination budget.
防衛省の機密費　暗殺の予算とともに姿を消した内部の人間
What do you think you're doing,
どういうつもりだ
Takaoka?
鷹岡
Episode
Takaoka Time
悪い子たちだ
What naughty children.
恩師に会うのに　裏口から来る
Slipping in through the back door to see your dear teacher?
That's not how your good old dad raised you.
父ちゃんはそんな子に育てたつもりはないぞ
Ah, well. I'll have to give you some summertime tutoring.
仕方ない　夏休みの補習をしてやろう
Takaoka... sensei...
鷹岡…先生
Shall we take this to the roof?
屋上へ行こうか
I've got everything ready to welcome my beloved students.
愛する生徒たちに歓迎の用意がしてあるんだ
You'll follow me up there, right?
ついてきてくれるよな
After all, your class is only alive thanks to my benevolence.
お前らのクラスは俺の慈悲で生かされているんだから
殺し屋を雇い　生徒たちをウイルスで脅すこの凶行
Hiring assassins, threatening students with a virus...
Have you gone mad?
血迷ったか
Now, now. I am exceedingly sane!
おいおいおい　俺は至極まともだぜ
これは地球が救える計画なんだ
This plan of mine will save the world!
If only you'd sent those two littl'uns along to bring me the one with the bounty,
おとなしくそこのちっこいの２人に賞金首を持ってこさせりゃ
my assassination plan would've gone off without a hitch.
俺の暗殺計画はスムーズに仕上がったのにな
See, my plan would've used,
what was her name, Kayano? The girl.
計画ではな　茅野とかいったっけ　女の方
そいつを使う予定だった
The bathub in my room here is filled with anti-teacher BBs.
部屋のバスタブに対殺せんせー弾がたっぷり入れてある
I'd have her go in there while holding the target,
そこに賞金首を抱いて入ってもらう
and then I'd bury them alive in cement.
その上からセメントで生き埋めにする
For him to return to his usual form without touching those BBs,
対せんせー弾に触れずに元の姿に戻すには
he would have to blow the lot to
smithereens—including his student.
生徒ごと爆裂しなきゃいけないって寸法さ
生徒思いの殺せんせーはそんなひどいことしないだろ
But he cares far too much for his dear students to do anything so heartless!
So I figure he'd just do me a favor and melt away without a fight.
おとなしく溶かされてくれると思ってな
He's...
あ…悪魔
He's a demon!
全員で乗り込んできたと知ったときは肝を冷やしたが
It gave me a fright when I learned you all came here together,
but it doesn't much change what I have to do.
やることは大して変わらない
My mood will determine how many of you leave here alive.
お前らを何人生かすかは俺の機嫌次第だからな
Do you think you can get away with this?
許されると思いますか　そんなまねが
Oh, I'd say it's far more humane than how you've treated me!
これでも人道的な方さ
お前らが俺にした非人道的な仕打ちに比べりゃな
Takaoka lost to a junior-high kid and totally blew his mission!
鷹岡のやつ　中学生に負けて任務に失敗したらしいぜ
Whoa! And after all that bragging about his teaching skills?
「教育だったら　俺に任せろ」って豪語してたのに
His bosses mustn't think much of him now!
上の評価　だだ下がりだってよ
Their humiliating glances, and that trick you pulled on me with a knife...
屈辱の目線とだまし討ちで突き付けられたナイフがよ
Whenever they cross my mind, my face gets so itchy I can't even sleep at night!
頭ん中ちらつくたびに顔がかゆくなってな
夜も眠れねえんだよ
I'll pay back my failure with results.
落とした評価は結果で返す
I'll take the humiliation I suffered and give it back in spades!
受けた屈辱はそれ以上の屈辱で返す
And you're first on my list, Shiota Nagisa!
特に　潮田渚
I will never forgive you for spoiling my future!
俺の未来を汚したお前は絶対に許さん
So when he asked for the shortest students, he was after Nagisa.
背の低い生徒を要求したのは　渚を狙ってたのか
A completely unjustified grudge!
完璧な逆恨みじゃねえか
Oh? So you wanted Nagisa-kun here so you could settle the score?
つまり　渚君はあんたの恨みを晴らすために呼ばれたわけ
Would it make you happy, beating someone so much smaller than you?
その体格差で勝って　本気でうれしい
I could show you a much better time
俺ならもっと楽しませてやれるけど
You're nuts. You only lost to Nagisa according to your own damn rules!
いかれやがって
てめえで作ったルールの中で渚に負けただけだろうが
言っとくけどな　あんとき　てめえが勝ってようが負けてようが
Listen, whether you'd won or lost back then,
俺ら　てめえのこと　大っ嫌いだからよ
we'd still hate your guts!
ジャリどもの意見なんざ聞いてねえ
I don't recall asking you little shits for your opinions!
Don't forget I could blow away half of you with one finger!
俺の指先でジャリが半分減るってこと忘れんな
You. Shrimp.
ちび　お前１人で上ってこい
Come upstairs alone.
この上のヘリポートまで
To the heliport.
Nagisa, you can't!
渚　駄目　行ったら
I don't want to...
行きたくないけど…
but I will.
行くよ
Get a move on! Now!
早く来い　おらぁ
あれだけ興奮してたら　何するか分からない
He's so agitated that who knows what he'll do.
I'll hear him out, talk him down,
話を合わせて冷静にさせて
and get him to hand over the remedy in one piece.
治療薬を壊さないよう　渡してもらうよ
Nagisa-kun...
渚君
渚…
Nagisa...
Takaoka!
鷹岡
おーっと勘違いするなよ
Now, now, don't take this the wrong way.
I just don't want you interrupting my precious time with Shiota Nagisa-kun.
これは俺と潮田渚君との大切な時間を邪魔されたくないためだ
There. Now no one else can come up here.
これで　もう誰も上ってこれねえ
俺のやりたいことは分かるな
Do you understand what I'm trying to do?
この前のリターンマッチだ
This is a rematch of our earlier fight.
Wait, Takaoka-sensei.
待ってください　鷹岡先生
I didn't come here to fight.
闘いに来たわけじゃないんです
だろうな
I'm sure.
Those cheap tricks of yours won't work anymore.
この前みてえなひきょうな手はもう通じねえ
I can see myself doing you in, just like that.
一瞬で俺にやられるのは目に見えてる
But if I do, it'll be over too quickly to make me feel better.
だがな　一瞬で終わっちゃ　俺としても気が晴れねえ
So before we fight, there's something I need you to do.
だから　闘う前にやることやってもらわなくちゃな
謝罪しろ　土下座だ
Apologize. On your hands and knees.
Atone wholeheartedly for having pulled a dirty sneak attack
実力がないから ひきょうな手で奇襲した
それについて誠心誠意な
because you lack any real skill.
I—
僕は…
That doesn't look like hands and knees to me, you goddamned brat!
それが土下座か　バカがきが
I wanna see your head on the ground, boy!
頭　こすりつけて謝んだよ
I have no real skill, so I pulled a dirty sneak attack. I'm sorry.
僕は実力がないから　ひきょうな手で奇襲しました
ごめんなさい
Oh, and after that you talked real big to me. Told me to get out, as I recall.
おお　その後で偉そうな口もたたいたよな
「出ていけ」とか
Is that any way for a brat like you to talk to an adult?
がきの分際で　大人に向かって
Is that any way for a student to talk to his teacher?!
生徒が教師に向かってだぞ
I'm just a brat and a student,
がきのくせに　生徒のくせに
and it was wrong for me to talk back to an adult—a teacher.
大人の人に　先生に　生意気な口をたたいてしまい　すみませんでした
I'm very sorry.
本当にごめんなさい
よーし　やっと本心を言ってくれたな　父ちゃんはうれしいぞ
Now you're speaking from the heart.
Your dear dad is so pleased!
I'll let you in on a little something in return.
褒美にいいことを教えてやろう
I asked Smog what happens to people who die from that virus.
ウイルスで死んだやつがどうなるか
スモッグのやつに画像を見せてもらったんだが　笑えるぜ
He showed me some pictures. What a laugh!
Their bodies, covered in boils!
全身できものだらけ　顔がブドウみたいに腫れ上がってな
Faces like bunches of grapes!
Wouldn't you like to see that, Nagisa-kun?
見たいだろ　渚君
No!
やめろー
Yes!
そう　その顔が見たかった
That's the face I wanted to see!
You ought to keep a summer journal, like you'd do for plants,
夏休みの観察日記にしたらどうだ
and write down every detail as your friends' faces bubble in agony!
お友達の顔面がブドウみたいに化けていく様をよ
I'll... kill you...
殺…してやる
That's right.
そうだ　そうでなくっちゃな
That's the way.
Oh dear...
I'll...
こ…殺してやる
I'll kill you!
太陽が射す　閉ざした瞼の裏側に赤い残像
The sun shines
taiyou ga sasu
On the back of my closed eyelids
tozashita mabuta no uragawa ni
I see red afterimages
akai zanzou
With a notebook and a pen in my leather bag
kawa no kaban ni nooto to pen wo
革の鞄に　ノートとペンを　さあ歩き出そう
I go for a walk
saa arukidasou
描いても描いても　綺麗にならない
I keep drawing, but I can't get it to look pretty
kaitemo kaitemo kirei ni naranai
My choice of colors is not to blame
eranda enogu ni tsumi wa nai
選んだ絵の具に　罪はない
I still remember the shooting star I saw last night
kinou no yonaka ni mita nagareboshi mada oboeteiru
昨日の夜中に見た流れ星　まだ覚えている
I was waiting for…
I was waiting for...
Hello shooting-star Hello shooting-star again
Hello, shooting star
Hello, shooting star, again
I was waiting
matteita yo
待っていたよ
夢を見るあの子はずっと
The girl of many dreams
yume wo miru ano ko wa zutto
ここにいるの　Ah　Ah
Is always here
koko ni iru no
あの日のまま　Ah　Ah
Just like you did that day
ano hi no mama
また光って
Shine again
mata hikatte
三年Ｅ組の皆さん　今日までよく頑張りました
これからもよく学び　よく遊び　よく殺せ
殺せんせーの暗殺教室　１学期
これにて　終業